<?xml version = "1.0" encoding = "utf-8"?> 
<data>
	<!-- Any changes here will carry throughout the entire project -->
	<title>Chaotic Automata</title>
	<authors>Rushy Panchal and George Georges.</authors>
	<copyright>&#169; <!--Copyright Symbol --> Rushy Panchal and George Georges 2014.</copyright>
	<about>
		<!-- About CA Text -->
		What is Cellular Automata?
			Cellular Automata is a simulation of the life and death of various entities that affect each other. 
			A typical Automaton consists of a grid (though other arrangements are also common) of "cells" that have one of numerous states.
			This project uses a binary system, so a cell can either be ON or OFF.

			The Automaton evolves by following a set of discrete rules.
			For example, a popular implementation of Cellular Automata, Conway's Game of Life, turns on a cell when two of its adjacent cells are currently on.
			A cell is turned off, however, if more than three of its adjacent cells are on. This implementation also uses a binary system..

			By applying these rules repeatedly, the various generations can become increasingly complex and form very intricate patterns.

			An Automaton can be Totalistic or Non-Totalistic, and can exist in more than one dimension.
			A Totalistic Automaton only counts the number of neighboring cells; a Non-Totalistic considers the arrangement of the neighboring cells as well.
			Our program allows the choice of the dimension, as well as the cell of interest, rules, and initial state.

		Cellular Automata Terms
			Automaton - Entire evolving system
			Cell - Singular entity that can affect other entities
			State - Variance of cell (can be ON or OFF in Chaotic Automata)
			Rules - A set of predefined laws that govern how a cell affects its neighboring cells
			Cell of Interest - The cell that is affected when a particular rule matches
			Cellstate - State and arrangement of the cells at a given generation

		Using the Program
			Every aspect of the program contains a "Help" button if it was necessary.
			These contain small, simple bits of text that help explain how the program works to the user.

			The user can input the following characteristics: Dimension, Cell of Interest, Rules, and Initial State.

		Features of Chaotic Automata:
			- 1-Dimensional (Non-Totalistic) and 2-Dimensional (Totalistic) Automata
			- Wrap mode
			- Supports an unlimited number of rules
			- Allows different Cells of Interest
			- Custom initial cellstate
			- Various Preset Examples
			- Automatic Automaton History Recording (can run previous automata)
			- Settings Editor (including Font, Fullscreen, Color, etc.)

		DEVELOPER DISCLAIMER

		Chaotic Automata is licensed under the General Public License (GPL) version 3.0.

		The source may be modified and/or distributed as open-source software, under the condition that the original creator names and license are provided and kept intact.

		The developers provide the software "as-is" and do not take any responsibility for any damage or harm caused by the software.
		Changing the source code may lead to unexpected results, and the developers do not have any liabilities toward this.

		GPL DISCLAIMER

		This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
		it under the terms of the GNU General Public License (version 3) as published by
		the Free Software Foundation.

		This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
		but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
		MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
		GNU General Public License for more details.

		Created by Rushy Panchal and George Georges. &#169; 2014. All rights reserved.
	</about>
	<help>
		<!-- Specific Help Text -->
		<settings>
			The width and height is the size of the Cellular Automata grids (in pixels).

			The program font and font size can also be changed, as well as fullscreen mode.
		</settings>
		<history>
			The user history is a record of all the previous automata run.

			By clicking on an automaton's number, more detailed information can be viewed about it.
			In addition, any history record can be deleted, or every item can be deleted using the "Clear" button.
		</history>
		<cellspace>
			The cellspace is the entire grid of cells.

			It can be 1 or 2 dimensional, and has a "wrap" mode. if wrap is enabled, the edges will wrap around to the other side.
		</cellspace>
		<interest>
			 The Cell of Interest is the cell that is turned on when a particular rule pattern is matched.
			 Generally, this is the center cell in the neighborhood, but it can be anything in the surrounding neighborhood.
			 
			 To select a cell, click on it.
			 Only one cell should be clicked (any other clicked cells will be disregarded).
		</interest>
		<rules>
			Rules are specific patterns that have to be matched.
			To select a cell in the input grid, simply click on it.

			For 1-dimensional Cellular Automata, the cell of interest is turned to the "on" state only if the rule matches exactly.

			For 2-dimensional Automata, the cell of interest is turned on if the number of adjacent cells matches the amount of selected cells.

			The program will slow down if there are too many rules, but there is no defined limit.
		</rules>
		<draw>
			An initial cellstate can be selected by clicking or dragging the mouse on the screen below.

			For 1-Dimensional Automata, only the first row is considered (the whole grid is used for 2-Dimensional).

			Presets can be selected from the Examples on the left. This will override the current settings.
			In addition, the automaton can be paused by pressing the "Pause" button. While paused, the current cellstate can be edited by using the "Edit" button.

			The current selected rules are displayed on the right side. However, to edit them, you must go back to the previous "Rules" screen.
		</draw>
	</help>
</data>